[Home](https://appuals.com/)_/_Privacy Policy of appuals.com

Privacy Policy of appuals.com
=============================

Users may be subject to different protection standards and broader standards may therefore apply to some. In order to learn more about the protection criteria, Users can refer to the applicability section. This document can be printed for reference by using the print command in the settings of any browser.

Owner and Data Controller
-------------------------

Appuals | Lytchett House, 13 Freeland Park, Wareham Road, Poole, Dorset, BH16 6FA  
Owner contact email: privacy@appuals.com

Types of Data collected
-----------------------

Among the types of Personal Data that appuals.com collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookies; Usage Data; unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example); email address; geographic position; language.

Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection. Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using appuals.com.

Unless specified otherwise, all Data requested by appuals.com is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for appuals.com to provide its services. In cases where appuals.com specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without consequences to the availability or the functioning of the Service.

Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.  
Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by appuals.com or by the owners of third-party services used by appuals.com serves the purpose of providing the Service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy, if available.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through appuals.com and confirm that they have the third party’s consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

Mode and place of processing the Data
-------------------------------------

**Methods of processing**

The Owner takes appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.

The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Owner, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of appuals.com (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Owner at any time.

**Legal basis of processing**

The Owner may process Personal Data relating to Users if one of the following applies:

* Users have given their consent for one or more specific purposes. Note: Under some legislations the Owner may be allowed to process Personal Data until the User objects to such processing (“opt-out”), without having to rely on consent or any other of the following legal bases. This, however, does not apply, whenever the processing of Personal Data is subject to European data protection law;
* provision of Data is necessary for the performance of an agreement with the User and/or for any pre-contractual obligations thereof;
* processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the Owner is subject;  
    processing is related to a task that is carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Owner;  
    processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner or by a third party.

In any case, the Owner will gladly help to clarify the specific legal basis that applies to the processing, and in particular whether the provision of Personal Data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract.

Place
-----

The Data is processed at the Owner’s operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved in the processing are located.

Depending on the User’s location, data transfers may involve transferring the User’s Data to a country other than their own. To find out more about the place of processing of such transferred Data, Users can check the section containing details about the processing of Personal Data.

If broader protection standards are applicable, Users are also entitled to learn about the legal basis of Data transfers to a country outside the European Union or to any international organization governed by public international law or set up by two or more countries, such as the UN, and about the security measures taken by the Owner to safeguard their Data.

If any such transfer takes place, Users can find out more by checking the relevant sections of this document or inquire with the Owner using the information provided in the contact section.

Retention time
--------------

Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been collected for.

**Therefore:**

Personal Data collected for purposes related to the performance of a contract between the Owner and the User shall be retained until such contract has been fully performed. Personal Data collected for the purposes of the Owner’s legitimate interests shall be retained as long as needed to fulfill such purposes. Users may find specific information regarding the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner within the relevant sections of this document or by contacting the Owner.

The Owner may be allowed to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever the User has given consent to such processing, as long as such consent is not withdrawn. Furthermore, the Owner may be obliged to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever required to do so for the performance of a legal obligation or upon order of an authority.

Once the retention period expires, Personal Data shall be deleted. Therefore, the right of access, the right to erasure, the right to rectification and the right to data portability cannot be enforced after expiration of the retention period.

**The purposes of processing**
------------------------------

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its Service, comply with its legal obligations, respond to enforcement requests, protect its rights and interests (or those of its Users or third parties), detect any malicious or fraudulent activity, as well as the following: Advertising, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Traffic optimization and distribution, Commercial affiliation, Tag Management, Remarketing and behavioral targeting, Content commenting, Analytics, Managing contacts and sending messages and Displaying content from external platforms.

For specific information about the Personal Data used for each purpose, the User may refer to the section “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data”.

**Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data**

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

This type of service allows User Data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes. These communications are displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on appuals.com, possibly based on User interests. This does not mean that all Personal Data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below.

Some of the services listed below may use Trackers to identify Users or they may use the behavioral retargeting technique, i.e. displaying ads tailored to the User’s interests and behavior, including those detected outside appuals.com. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.

Services of this kind usually offer the possibility to opt out of such tracking. In addition to any opt-out feature offered by any of the services below, Users may learn more on how to generally opt out of interest-based advertising within the dedicated section “How to opt-out of interest-based advertising” in this document.

**Google AdSense (Google LLC)**

Google AdSense is an advertising service provided by Google LLC. This service uses the “DoubleClick” Cookie, which tracks use of appuals.com and User behavior concerning ads, products and services offered.

Users may decide to disable all the DoubleClick Cookies by going to: [Google Ad Settings](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated?hl=en).  
In order to understand Google’s use of data, consult [Google’s partner policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites).  
Personal Data processed: Cookies; Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated).

**FlexOffers.com (FlexOffers.com, LLC)**

FlexOffers.com is an advertising service provided by FlexOffers.com, LLC.  
Personal Data processed: Cookies; Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.flexoffers.com/privacy-policy/).

**Mediavine (Mediavine, Inc.)**

Mediavine is an advertising service provided by Mediavine, Inc.  
Personal Data processed: Tracker; Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.mediavine.com/privacy-policy) – [Opt out](https://www.mediavine.com/privacy-policy).

**Mediavine Programmatic Advertising (Ver 1.0)**

The Website works with Mediavine to manage third-party interest-based advertising appearing on the Website. Mediavine serves content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use first and third-party cookies. A cookie is a small text file which is sent to your computer or mobile device (referred to in this policy as a “device”) by the web server so that a website can remember some information about your browsing activity on the Website.

First party cookies are created by the website that you are visiting. A third-party cookie is frequently used in behavioral advertising and analytics and is created by a domain other than the website you are visiting. Third-party cookies, tags, pixels, beacons and other similar technologies (collectively, “Tags”) may be placed on the Website to monitor interaction with advertising content and to target and optimize advertising. Each internet browser has functionality so that you can block both first and third-party cookies and clear your browser’s cache. The “help” feature of the menu bar on most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to receive notification of new cookies, how to disable existing cookies and how to clear your browser’s cache. For more information about cookies and how to disable them, you can consult the information at [All About Cookies](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/).

Without cookies you may not be able to take full advantage of the Website content and features. Please note that rejecting cookies does not mean that you will no longer see ads when you visit our Site. In the event you opt-out, you will still see non-personalized advertisements on the Website.

The Website collects the following data using a cookie when serving personalized ads:

* IP Address
* Operating System type
* Operating System version
* Device Type
* Language of the website
* Web browser type
* Email (in hashed form)

Mediavine Partners (companies listed below with whom Mediavine shares data) may also use this data to link to other end user information the partner has independently collected to deliver targeted advertisements. Mediavine Partners may also separately collect data about end users from other sources, such as advertising IDs or pixels, and link that data to data collected from Mediavine publishers in order to provide interest-based advertising across your online experience, including devices, browsers and apps. This data includes usage data, cookie information, device information, information about interactions between users and advertisements and websites, geolocation data, traffic data, and information about a visitor’s referral source to a particular website. Mediavine Partners may also create unique IDs to create audience segments, which are used to provide targeted advertising.

If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices to opt-in or opt-out of this data collection, please visit [National Advertising Initiative opt out page](https://thenai.org/opt-out/). You may also visit [Digital Advertising Alliance website](http://optout.aboutads.info/#/) and [Network Advertising Initiative website](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#) to learn more information about interest-based advertising. You may download the AppChoices app at [Digital Advertising Alliance’s AppChoices app](https://youradchoices.com/appchoices) to opt out in connection with mobile apps, or use the platform controls on your mobile device to opt out.

For specific information about Mediavine Partners, the data each collects and their data collection and privacy policies, please visit [Mediavine Partners](https://www.mediavine.com/ad-partners/).

This type of service allows appuals.com to display advertisements for third-party products or services. Ads can be displayed either as advertising links or as banners using various kinds of graphics. Clicks on the icon or banner posted on the Application are tracked by the third-party services listed below, and are shared with appuals.com.

For details of which data are collected, please refer to the privacy policy of each service.

**Amazon Affiliation (Amazon)**

Amazon Affiliation is a commercial affiliation service provided by Amazon.com Inc.  
Personal Data processed: Cookies; Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=hp_rel_topic?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496).

**CJ Affiliate by Conversant (Conversant, Inc.)**

CJ Affiliate by Conversant is a commercial affiliation service provided by Conversant, Inc.  
Personal Data processed: Cookies; Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](http://www.conversantmedia.com/legal/privacy).

This type of service allows you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of appuals.com and interact with them. This type of service might still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

**Google Fonts**

Google Fonts is a typeface visualization service provided by Google LLC or by Google Ireland Limited, depending on how the Owner manages the Data processing, that allows appuals.com to incorporate content of this kind on its pages. Personal Data processed: Usage Data; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy); Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

**Google Tag Manager (Google LLC)**

Google Tag Manager is a tag management service provided by Google LLC.  
Personal Data processed: Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

**Display Advertising extension for Google Analytics (Google Inc.)**

Google Analytics on appuals.com might use Google’s Interest-based advertising, 3rd-party audience data and information from the DoubleClick Cookie to extend analytics with demographics, interests and ads interaction data.

Personal Data processed: Cookies; Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

**Google Analytics with anonymized IP (Google Inc.)**

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of appuals.com, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.

Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.  
This integration of Google Analytics anonymizes your IP address. It works by shortening Users’ IP addresses within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the complete IP address be sent to a Google server and shortened within the US.

Personal Data processed: Cookies; Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

Content commenting services allow Users to make and publish their comments on the contents of appuals.com.  
Depending on the settings chosen by the Owner, Users may also leave anonymous comments. If there is an email address among the Personal Data provided by the User, it may be used to send notifications of comments on the same content. Users are responsible for the content of their own comments.

If a content commenting service provided by third parties is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the comment service is installed, even when Users do not use the content commenting service.  
Disqus (Disqus)

Disqus is a content commenting service provided by Big Heads Labs Inc.  
Personal Data processed: Cookies; Usage Data; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://help.disqus.com/customer/portal/articles/466259-privacy-policy) – [Opt out](https://help.disqus.com/customer/portal/articles/1657951).  

This type of service allows interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of appuals.com.

The interaction and information obtained through appuals.com are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network.

This type of service might still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

It is recommended to log out from the respective services in order to make sure that the processed data on appuals.com isn’t being connected back to the User’s profile.

**Facebook Like button and social widgets (Facebook, Inc.)**

The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook, Inc.

Personal Data processed: Cookies; Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation).

**Twitter Tweet button and social widgets (Twitter, Inc.)**

The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter, Inc.

Personal Data processed: Cookies; Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/privacy).

**Reddit button and widgets (reddit inc.)**

The reddit button and widgets are services allowing interaction with the reddit platform provided by reddit inc.

Personal Data processed: Cookies; Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.reddit.com/help/privacypolicy).

**AddThis (Oracle Corporation)**

AddThis is a service provided by Oracle Corporation, which displays a widget that allows interaction with social networks and external platforms as well as sharing the contents of appuals.com.

Depending on the configuration, this service can display widgets belonging to third parties such as the managers of social networks where interactions are shared. In this case, also the third parties that provide the widget will be informed of interactions and Usage Data on the pages where this service is installed.

Personal Data processed: Cookies; Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.oracle.com/legal/privacy/addthis-privacy-policy.html).

This type of service allows appuals.com and its partners to inform, optimize and serve advertising based on past use of appuals.com by the User.

This activity is facilitated by tracking Usage Data and by using Trackers to collect information which is then transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioral targeting activity.

Some services offer a remarketing option based on email address lists.

In addition to any opt-out feature provided by any of the services below, Users may opt out by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1).

**Users may also opt-out of certain advertising features through applicable device settings, such as the device advertising settings for mobile phones or ads settings in general**.

**Remarketing with Google Analytics (Google LLC)**

Remarketing with Google Analytics is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Google LLC that connects the tracking activity performed by Google Analytics and its Cookies with the Google Ads advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie.

Personal Data processed: Cookies; Usage Data.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated).

This type of service allows appuals.com to distribute their content using servers located across different countries and to optimize their performance.

Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and the way these services are implemented.

Their function is to filter communications between appuals.com and the User’s browser.

Considering the widespread distribution of this system, it is difficult to determine the locations to which the contents that may contain Personal Information of the User are transferred.

**Cloudflare (Cloudflare)**

Cloudflare is a traffic optimization and distribution service provided by Cloudflare Inc.

The way Cloudflare is integrated means that it filters all the traffic through appuals.com, i.e., communication between appuals.com and the User’s browser, while also allowing analytical data from appuals.com to be collected.

Personal Data processed: Cookies; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.cloudflare.com/security-policy/).

In addition to any opt-out feature provided by any of the services listed in this document, Users may learn more on how to generally opt out of interest-based advertising within the dedicated section of the Cookie Policy.

The rights of Users
-------------------

Users may exercise certain rights regarding their Data processed by the Owner.

Users entitled to broader protection standards may exercise any of the rights described below. In all other cases, Users may inquire with the Owner to find out which rights apply to them.

**In particular, Users have the right to do the following:**

Withdraw their consent at any time. Users have the right to withdraw consent where they have previously given their consent to the processing of their Personal Data.

Object to processing of their Data. Users have the right to object to the processing of their Data if the processing is carried out on a legal basis other than consent. Further details are provided in the dedicated section below.

Access their Data. Users have the right to learn if Data is being processed by the Owner, obtain disclosure regarding certain aspects of the processing and obtain a copy of the Data undergoing processing.  
Verify and seek rectification. Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their Data and ask for it to be updated or corrected.

Restrict the processing of their Data. Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to restrict the processing of their Data. In this case, the Owner will not process their Data for any purpose other than storing it.  
Have their Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed. Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to obtain the erasure of their Data from the Owner.

Receive their Data and have it transferred to another controller. Users have the right to receive their Data in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format and, if technically feasible, to have it transmitted to another controller without any hindrance. This provision is applicable provided that the Data is processed by automated means and that the processing is based on the User’s consent, on a contract which the User is part of or on pre-contractual obligations thereof.

Lodge a complaint. Users have the right to bring a claim before their competent data protection authority.  
Details about the right to object to processing

Where Personal Data is processed for a public interest, in the exercise of an official authority vested in the Owner or for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner, Users may object to such processing by providing a ground related to their particular situation to justify the objection.

Users must know that, however, should their Personal Data be processed for direct marketing purposes, they can object to that processing at any time without providing any justification. To learn, whether the Owner is processing Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, Users may refer to the relevant sections of this document.

**How to exercise these rights**

Any requests to exercise User rights can be directed to the Owner through the contact details provided in this document. These requests can be exercised free of charge and will be addressed by the Owner as early as possible and always within one month.

**Applicability of broader protection standards**

While most provisions of this document concern all Users, some provisions expressly only apply if the processing of Personal Data is subject to broader protection standards.

**Such broader protection standards apply when the processing:**

is performed by an Owner based within the EU;

* concerns the Personal Data of Users who are in the EU and is related to the offering of paid or unpaid goods or services, to such Users;
* concerns the Personal Data of Users who are in the EU and allows the Owner to monitor such Users’ behavior taking place in the EU.

**Appuals.com uses Trackers. To learn more, the User may consult the Cookie Policy.**

**Additional information about Data collection and processing** 

**Legal action**

The User’s Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Owner in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of appuals.com or the related Services.  
The User declares to be aware that the Owner may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.

**Additional information about User’s Personal Data**

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, appuals.com may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular Services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.

**System logs and maintenance**

For operation and maintenance purposes, appuals.com and any third-party services may collect files that record interaction with appuals.com (System logs) use other Personal Data (such as the IP Address) for this purpose.

**Information not contained in this policy**

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Owner at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.

**How “Do Not Track” requests are handled**

Appuals.com does not support “Do Not Track” requests.  
To determine whether any of the third-party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies.

**Changes to this privacy policy**

The Owner reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by notifying its Users on this page and possibly within appuals.com and/or – as far as technically and legally feasible – sending a notice to Users via any contact information available to the Owner. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom.

Should the changes affect processing activities performed on the basis of the User’s consent, the Owner shall collect new consent from the User, where required.

**Appuals.com**  
_part of PYCO IT SOLUTIONS LTD registered in England & Wales under 08166026_  
Lytchett House, 13 Freeland Park, Wareham Road, Poole, Dorset, BH16 6FA, UK  
**E:** editor@appuals.com **|** **T:** +44 161 870 6764

Search for:  

 Search for

 Search for
